BOLUWATIFE POPOOLA

ADDRESS

Ikeja, Lagos. Ilorin, Kwara-state Lagos 100212

- Ikeja, Lagos., Ilorin, Kwara-state, Lagos 100212
- **+2348167138572** ■ olaoyejnr@gmail.com
- **y** @iam_prometheus
- Prometheo
- in Popoola Boluwatife

OBJECTIVE

I am a Software Engineer adept in building highly functional Rest services, web apps and desktop apps using python and javascript and writing smart contracts with solidity. I always look to contribute extensively to any project i am involved in, technically and in other aspects, learn as much as i can and become a valuable asset to the team. i love taking on tasks that require extensive research and i do it well.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Gotahia Stores Software Engineer

(September 2020 - Present)

- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code for the backend api.
- Wrote comprehensive unit-tests for all features delivered
- Provided proper documentation for all endpoints delivered.
- Brainstorm to solve complex problems and and write efficient code to solve, a typical example was building a solution for our complex pricing strategy, which resulted in plaudits from my team lead and members for my implementation.
- Made use of tools and services such as amazon s3, cloudinary, redis etc.

LinuxJobber

(January 2020 - March 2020)

Full Stack developer Intern

- Developed full stack scrum application for managers to manage projects with Django and Angularjs.
- Made use of amazon s3 bucket and ec2 instance for deployment services.

Hotels Ng Internships

(June 2020 - August 2020)

Python Developer Intern

- Collaborated with teams to deliver highly functional microservices on time.
- Made use of tools and services such as docker for containerizing our apps, cloudinary for serving assets and amazon ses for our email api.

React

javascript

REST APIs

Postgresql

Swagger Documentation

Proficient

Proficient

Docker

Familiar

Proficient

Among the Top Hundred Finalists out of over 8 thousand Interns that started the Internship.

Minority Programmers

(July 2021 - Present)

Blockchain Developer

- Implemented, tested and audited smart contracts for the inctive based learning tokens.
- Designed, Implemented and tested the Governance token smart contract to be used in community voting.
- Hooked up smart contract to Front end pages using react, next and ethers.js

SKILLS

Python

Very Good Django

Proficient

Solidity Proficient

AWS

Familiar

Proficient

Flask

web3 **Proficient**

Github Actions

Proficient

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Hackathon NFT Certificate Idle Finance and Defi Summer

Won a Hackathon sponsored by Idle.finance: Certificate

LinkedIn Assessment

LinkedIn

Passed the LinkedIn assessment test for Python, Profile

Blockchain basics

University of Buffalo

completed Blockchain Course on Cousera, Certificate

Data Science Foundation

IBM

completed the data science foundation course and test with IBM

Data Manipulation with Pandas

DataCamp

completed the Data Manipulation course and project

EDUCATION

University of Ilorin

(August 2014 - September 2019)

Bachelor's Degree Botany

PROJECTS

Email microservice https://email-microdev.herokuapp.com/

Built a mailing microservice for sending of email, using services such as smtp and amazon ses. with the django rest framework. github link: https://github.com/Prometheo/email-microapi

Movie rating API

https://bento-movies.herokuapp.com

Built an API to rate and add movies to personal collections.

Remote camera player(Desktop App)

https://github.com/Prometheo/project-nigeria

Built a remote cam player, for playing cctv videos. made use of the pyqt6 gui library and python vlc wrapper

currency converter

https://convert-my-currency.netlify.app/

i built a currency converter app using django and angular as front end, my app gets the latest exchange rates for about 166 different currencies. django git link: https://github.com/Prometheo/finance-microapi angular git link: https://github.com/Prometheo/financial-app

HOBBIES Gaming

Football(Playing and Watching)

history and biographies. **Blockchain Enthusiast**

LANGUAGES English

Fluent

Spanish conversational